thank you for joining the earnings
conference call of Isis a lombard for q1
fi 2021 I would like to give you a brief
overview of the recent developments in
the industry and in our responses to
them post which our CFO mr. Gopal valla
tendrán will share the financial
performance of the company now as you
you know we know this and you know as we
speak today we are seeing rising cases
of covert 19 in the country
well that's happening and there is a
level of uncertainty surrounding the
pandemic you know that remains various
major measures taken by policymakers to
restart commerce and create are showing
results as such we believe that the
complete complete halt of activities
that we witnessed knave till may be
behind us and the new normal may well be
about learning to live with the virus
following safety protocols but ensuring
a gradual return to normalcy not Isis a
numbered we believe that it is important
to take extra measures to support our
customers in these challenging times
forcing the dis forcing the difficulties
arising due to the pandemic we decided
to provide some relevant covers to our
customers accordingly we have launched a
number of covered 19 specific health
insurance products we have also revamped
our existing health insurance products
by adding customer centric features for
new customers purchasing health
insurance policy will reduce the waiting
period to launch a cove in nineteen
relate claim from 30 days to 15 days
this is a initial wait period that we
have considering the economic
uncertainty financial security has
gained utmost significance for our
customers so we decided to retain the
cumulative bonus accumulated by
customers over time even if the large
covert 19 related hospitalization claim
in the normal circumstances this would
not be so most importantly we added home
health care benefit for of customers
preferring to avail treatment in the
safety and comfort of their homes rather
than getting hospitalized to highlight
these upgraded health insurance
solutions we have launched a new health
insurance focus campaign restart right I
hope all of you've seen the campaign
during our earnings call for FY 2020 we
had shared with you a host of digital
initiatives that we took to service our
customers
and enable our channel partners to
conduct business we continue to give
trust to adoption of these digital
platforms in the quarter under review
review our new mobile you know service
app I will take care that was extended
to the retail customer segments crossed
one leg thirty thousand downloads in
happening more and more customers to
avail insurance and wellness solutions
at their fingertips the tele consult
feature available through this app
enable customers to seek medical advice
from the safe environment of their home
in case of property segments we harness
Virgie virtual platforms and
technological add forms including drones
for conducting claim service remotely
for small value wherein claims we
introduce a do-it-yourself mode
empowering our customers to conduct self
assessment of the damage and receive
real-time claim approval from our
customer service team for the diversity
of stakeholders including customers
investors etcetera I would like to
appraise you that we have begun
integrating ehe principles across our
businesses towards this we have
implemented policies and initiatives
aimed at scaling up our efforts towards
sustainable value creation let me now
talk about the industry trends in the
last few weeks we have been witnessing
signs of green shoots across sectors as
more and more industries are up to
digitization and restart operations
business activity should continue to
grow the non-life insurance industry
which witnessed a blip in the in the
first quarter q1 of grade 21 should
register a growth in the coming quarters
we believe for the recently concluded
quarter the general insurance industry
registered at the growth of 4.2% you
know in q1 of 2021 over q1 2020 with the
industry GDP moving down to rupees three
ninety three point two nine billion
rupees in q1 2021 from 410 point seven
two billion rupees in q1 of FY 2020 this
is as per GI Council report excluding
the crop segment with Jake Jay and the
generations industry degree were 3.2
percent two rupees three seventy eight
point five four billion rupees in q1
2021 as compared to 391 point zero eight
billion rupees in q1 of FY 2020 now
within this
the segment's such as motor insurance
has been severely impacted during the
lockdown and but they're now gaining
some the month of June for the segment
has witnessed signs of recovery though
we are still far from the long-term
average on the other hand health
insurance has benefited from the
heightened concern around the health
hazard and measures taken by the
government as new health insurance
policies registered an upsurge we
believe that the pandemic wave will be a
trigger for the segment to witness
significant increase in penetration in
the near future now as far as the
commercial lines are concerned the fire
segments continue to show robust growth
due to the rate hike with effect from
January 1 2020 we've talked about this
in the past marine and engineering lines
witness V growth due to the slowdown in
economic activity however as the economy
is steadily improving and given the
digital adoption by this segment we
expect to see a rebound
since our FY 2020 results called music
we witnessed new relatively
announcements there are focused on
policyholder benefits these include
first the launch of standardized health
insurance policy called RFQ sanjivini
with effect from April 1 2020 wherein
the authority has allowed insurers to
determine the price on compliance with
specific norms initially under the
policy the sum insured allowed was
between rupees 1 lakh to 5 lakhs further
the authority wide by rate circular
dated July 7th allowed the insurers to
issue policies with some insured less
than one left and greater than 5 lakh
which and this has to be in multiples of
50,000 rupees the second has been the
withdrawal of withdrawal of the option
of long term package effective age of
this first 2020 this means that new
vehicle customers will not be able to
avail own damage covers on long-term
cases going forward this is expected to
have marginal impact on business and
profitability allowing general and
health insurers to this is third one
allow help general and health insurers
to offer both in the median benefit
based short-term health insurance
policies for covert 90 it's also
prescribed a standard benefit based
health policy and a retail standard
health policy under the nomenclature
Kovalchuk shock policy for benefit
and and koruna code coverage policy for
indemnity respectively while the corona
coverage policy was mandated to be
offered on or before July 10th 20
insurers are encouraged to offer the
coroner RockShox policy by July 10th
now as I conclude my address I would
like to summarize that we are well
positioned to navigate through this
dynamically changing risk environment
given the strength of our franchise
diverse a diverse read product and
distribution portfolio and most
importantly the trust of our customers
we continue to remain focused on
creating long-term value for our
shareholders through prudent risk
selection and system phases sustain
profitability
I will now request Gopal to take you
through the financial numbers so the
recently concluded quarter thanks wag of
and good evening everyone hope everyone
is staying safe and healthy I will now
give you a brief overview on the
financial performance of the company for
the quarter ended June 30 2020 we have
put up the results presentation on our
website you can access it as we walk you
through the performance numbers the
gross direct Wingham income of the
company should read rupees thirty three
point zero two billion in quarter one as
compared to rupees thirty four point
eight seven billion in quarter one of
the last year adi growth of 5.3%
excluding crop segments our GDP I
decreased to rupees thirty two point
seven four billion in this quarter as
compared to rupees thirty four point
eight eight million in Porter one of
last year registering will be grow to
six point two percent our GDP growth was
primarily driven by our focus on
preferred segments
consequent to the increase in minimum
prescribed rates for certain occupancy
centerfire segment this segment
registered a robust GDP growth of 41.6%
in quarter one twenty twenty-one they're
fading GDP growth of our property and
casualty segments as indicated in our
results presentation the overall
property and casualty segments grew by
twenty point five percent in quarter one
twenty twenty one over quarter one
twenty twenty on the retail side of the
business SME and agency channel and
health in the military continued to grow
faster and remain our areas of focus to
harness a potential of these segments we
have been expanding our distribution
network so as to increase penetration
entire three
entire four cities our individual agents
which includes the point of sale
distribution where 49,000 802 as at June
30 2020 as against 47,000 548 as on
March 31 2020 the long term motor
penetration for private cars stood at
19.8 percent for quarter 1 2021 from 17
percent in quarter one of 2020 and for
two wheelers it stood at eleven point
three percent for quarter one twenty
twenty one from seventeen point five
percent in quarter one twenty twenty the
advanced premium was rupees thirty point
3 1 billion as the June 30 2020 from
pillar three point two five billion as
at mass thirty one twenty twenty
combined ratio stood at ninety nine
point seven percent in this quarter as
compared to one hundred point four
percent in quarter one of last year
combined ratio was ninety eight point
four percent in this quarter excluding
the impacts of cyclone Hansen and
missile go which had an impact of 0.3 1
billion rupees as compared to
ninety-nine point seven percent in
quarter one of last year excluding the
impact of cyclone Fanny which had an
impact of point one six billion rupees
our investment assets rose to rupees two
eighty one point one eight billion as
June 30 2020 as compared to rupees two
sixty three point two seven billion at
mass 31 2020 our investment leveraged
net of borings was four point two three
times at June 30 2020 as compared to
four point two one times at March 31
2008 income decrease two rupees four
point nine nine billion in quarter one
this year compared to rupees five point
two seven billion in quarter of last
year mainly on account of lower capital
gains overload our capital gains was
lower body 56.1%
I propose 0.6 zero being in quarter one
this year compared to the peas one point
three eight billion in quarter one of
last year our profit before tax grew by
eleven point seven percent to up is
five point three three 1 billion in this
quarter compared to rupees four point
seven five billion in quarter one of
last year on account of lower capital
gains consequently profit after tax grew
by 28.5 percent to rupee three point
nine eight bill
in quarter one this year as against
rupees three point ten billion in
quarter one of last year primarily due
to the lower effective tax rate of 25
percent return on average equity was
twenty five point one percent for this
quarter as compared to 23 percent for
quarter one of last year solvency ratio
was two point five times at June 30 as
against two point one seven times at
mass thirty one twenty twenty continued
to be higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 as I conclude my
address I would like to reiterate that
we entered quarter one twenty twenty one
with a diversified product portfolio and
healthy financials we continue to focus
on prudent underwriting technological
progress and introducing relevant and
timely this marriage prediction for our
customers we will stay focused on
driving long term growth in a
sustainable manner I would like to thank
you all for obtaining this earnings
conference call and we would be happy to
take any questions that you have thank
you thank you very much we will now
begin the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask questions
matrice star and one on the touch-tone
telephone if you wish to remove yourself
from the question you may press star 2
participants are requested to use
handset for asking questions ladies and
gentlemen we will wait for a moment
while the question queue assembles
to ask questions
star and one the first question is from
the line of Shh company from Macquarie
please go ahead
here hi good evening everyone
we did you are seeing after a long time
that you have had an underwriting profit
now if I where to look I have a closer
look there has been a good change as
well as expense management I mean how
long do you think I mean how much of
this is sustainable as it got to do with
the fact that the knockdowns have been
there and therefore the Thames have been
lower or works for moments resulted in
lower expenses just something more
qualitative that you can share on the
overall claims as well as expense
management the second question is the
retail indemnity of course is done very
well again any anecdotal evidence or
qualitative feedback from corporates
they're really going for more of the
group policies that people are taking
more retail indemnity based product
that's something which you would like to
know and finally the motor OD and third
party losses have actually gone down
quite substantially the loss ratios
whereas higher marine engineering is
picked up is it just a seasonal thing or
maybe something something got to do with
some even which is occurred this
particular water so let me address a
third one first it's you know short
response so let me get it done with you
know this quarter we had the cyclone you
know losses that gopal talked about and
one or two marine losses noncyclic
related that's why and as you know these
businesses are episodic it could be that
you know certain quarter you will have a
loss so it will go up but on an average
for the year is what we look at these
numbers so as I said jump the quarterly
volatility doesn't really you know
really concern us in that sense we would
look at what is the picture over the
over the whole year and cyclone
often particularly had some impact in
terms of the underwriting number and the
sustainability thereof
look there has been obviously some
benefit on the claim side this quarter
in terms of frequencies coming down and
if you look at difference
this is in line with what we are talked
about in way when we are doing the last
quarter's earnings called last year's
earnings call we had said that we would
expect and we were seeing some reduction
in frequency in the motor side we had
also talked about the frequency
reduction in the health side when it
came to the plant surgery cases and now
as you understand it at this point in
time unless you really need to go to the
hospital nor as we would want to go to
the hospital so these are benefits that
has come through and we also said that
we will see some of these going up in a
string stabilized annex and it
normalizes the wave we have looked at
this is these are not something that so
for example health in health we why
there has been a benefit in the quarter
our approach to reserving and actual
practices bit conservative we do you
know worry about Kovac claims going up
it is going up as we speak
and so we would want to take the full
benefit of the reduced frequency in the
first quarter and then end up having to
have a very high frequency in the last
quarter so we would want to watch this
for a whole year period and then take a
call on on what does the appropriate
loss for the year so there is a you know
so there is some benefit but it's not
entirely kind of factored in the first
quarter and in terms of cost look
obviously like every company we are
looking at all you know in essence
unnecessary costs that we can cut down
upon these are some obvious areas which
everyone would be doing but certain
areas where we believe it makes sense to
invest you are actually investing so one
you know as a company you've actually
given increment to our people we had
given performance bonus in the first
quarter you know to during the board
meeting we decided on the increment sort
for four people so and where we are
seeing opportunity in this at this point
in time for the long term because we
believe we can see this as an
opportunity invest of the future so
there would be
abilities that we may even increase our
headcount going ahead so it's not the
savings on the fix causes not on the
employ side and employees causes the
biggest cost element so savings will be
in terms of other you know areas of cost
that we can contain and do remember that
for us the sourcing causes a large part
of the cost so if we have lower retail
numbers in a period the sourcing course
is also low you know for that quarter
and lastly on technology we are actually
you know we've decided to increase our
technology budget and you invest more
and we see in the long term the
experience that we've had in this period
in the long term we believe we will take
some positives out of this in terms of
the way we work the way we operate how
much we work from home how much
flexibility we provide how much of
further investment in digitization we
are at a certain level relative to the
market but still we believe this is time
to keep investing and stay ahead of the
curve and that's an area where we are
further seeing how we can in this lastly
your second question in terms of
indemnity yes you are right I mean there
is as I said you know in the covering
you know opening remarks also I made the
point that there is high demand for
indemnity both from the corporate and
even more from the retail side one thing
you remember is that our retail health
book and you know if you see our overall
health book there is a corporate segment
there is a B to B to C segment which is
business that we source through our
bancassurance partners if is
fundamentally tales but does it get
classified under group because it's B to
B to C and third is a pure B to C which
is usually in the middle that we sell
largely through agents etc the retailer
in Demitri business has done really well
but the B to B to C obviously because
banks are not dispersing as much as they
were in the past that has grown so
unbalanced we are we are quite happy
with the help
opportunity and the growth that we are
seeing at this point in time and we
believe it is it is potentially a step
change and does not go on for health
insurance in the long term and you know
one of the things that we are seeing is
not just new customers we also seeing
existing customers are for someone
Thanks Thanks and there's a good amount
for this anodized Dell product right
er okay it's just recently launched we
think if you have a decent demand in
certain markets and take them to the
market thank you I think it's a good
product that the relator has launched it
will probably increase penetration in
segments which otherwise you are not
buying integers thank you thank you the
next question is from the line of shreya
Shivani from CRS a please go ahead yeah
thank you for the opportunity so I was
going to the slide which talks about the
impact of catastrophic events and we
know that in short for general insurance
there is a catastrophic trigger that a
certain level you will actually have
that catastrophic bond which will get
triggered
so can you throw some light on since we
had certain cyclones and floods this
quarter and also with Kovac 19 going on
if you can really talk about how are we
managing the losses in the catastrophes
are going around and how close or far
are we from that trigger which you know
which will trigger the bond the
catastrophic ball thank you well we are
not catastrophic bond these are you know
cat reinsurance that we buy every
company buys and it it triggers not in a
sense that you have to accumulate losses
for the year and then it triggers it is
an event best river so when a when a
cyclone happens if the aggregate losses
cross that threshold that we you know we
buy the cover from then the reinsurance
pay and we have to you know then we have
to spend a little bit of money which is
pre agreed to reinstate that cover so
basically what it does is very high very
large cat losses our balance sheet is
predicted and we pay a fee to buy that
production it's almost like you are
buying motor insurance for your motor
car you know it's like our book that we
are protecting through our insurance
cover it's not a cat bond and in terms
of specifics of what has happens to even
this year
then the armful happens and we get
claims maybe X inside that's slightly
gone above our you know trigger
threshold so it will trigger and we will
get some return from the reinsurer but
you know our balance sheet is there and
all of that is actually factored into
the quarterly numbers at UC Cooper you
want to add anything yes I think the
only thing that I will just add is I
think in line with what we have
communicated I think the trigger point
for a catastrophic loss in terms of
what's the heat that we take on the PNL
that number is at about 25 crores and of
course so that's that's the maximum
weight that we take in the event of any
catastrophic event that arises and over
and above that as what they've explained
I think obviously depending on the
extent of recovery that we make on the
reinsurance program we will obviously
have to pay the xml cost
so so far as the current couple of
catastrophic events are concerned and so
far a cyclone and fun is concerned I
think the extent of losses that came and
hit on the neck is in excess of the 25
crores restored so that's so to that
extent our claims is impacted by 25
crores and the excess will be repaid by
the reinsurers and insofar as cyclone
nargis concerned i think that has not
had a large impact in so far as our
claim numbers are concerned in the
aggregate as we mentioned as a part of
the opening remarks both of these events
put together all the claims we have
added impact of about 31 crews okay
thank you said understood thank you the
next question is from the line of a jock
Street Frederick from bhp securities
please go ahead thanks for taking my
question sir so my question is daddy's
health and what strategies are we
adopting to you place this big
opportunity that's out there that's one
and two is the competitive Soudan is it
because of banks slowing down and what
portion of our business is coming
through banks particularly the indemnity
return limited so that's on health
yeah so again and I lost 1g to expand on
this we answer to the second part is yes
as I said you know because we have a
larger part of our health distribution
and these are not necessarily indemnity
this includes retail benefit products
and since we traditionally have a larger
footprint from the bancassurance
partnership side on the retail health
the impact on health for us has been a
you know pretty severe on that end
just to give you a sense last year we
had roughly about 68 percent of our
retail business then this retail
includes your retail as also the b2b to
see direct afterwards 68 percent of the
business was you know business that we
got from the these kind of partnerships
and 32 percent was you know pure direct
one-to-one on sales that number from the
industry will be very different it will
be probably very high for one-on-one
sales and very low for medicine so that
definitely has had some impact for us
this quarter but within that the agency
piece which is you know individual sales
that's done really well for us and while
it's not cover up the you know gap on
the bancassurance side but it's it's
very bleak you know outperformed is our
view of what's happened on the market in
terms of the strategy look you know
there are multiple levers of strategy
one of course is the whole focus on
product and distribution and you've seen
the whole host of you know products that
we've launched recently one of the
things that we've been doing for the
last two years is significant
significantly expanding on our agency
distribution as I said Bank Asians were
already already strong and there's been
some regular changes in the over three
four years back which has also triggered
this initiative from our side there are
certain constraints that have gone away
for us and and that's something that we
are driving the other thing that we are
also doing is we entire approach that we
are taking to help is to say that we are
not just focusing on pure sickness
insurance where you go to a hospital and
we pay the reimburse the claim we are
thinking through
with a very customer centric you know
point of view in terms of what all do
you really worry about as an individual
and can we find solutions to each one of
them so one of them being wisest
hospitalisation why can't we cover you
know outpatient kick you know care and
for group customers and B to B to C
customers we've launched OPD covers last
year that's that was doing quite well I
mean you know the bancassurance Peter
has gone a bit slow this quarter but so
that's one for example and there we
worked or with network of partners
digital health players kelly calling you
know telling health companies you know
wellness service companies and all of
this is being provided on a digital
platform it's an app which we call i'll
take care i talked about that in my
opening remarks and in this period one
of the things that we did want to drive
versus you know in the long term also
will be wanting to drive this digital
health and but in this period that was
obviously something that we kind of
scaled up included home health care
because you know for small you know
issues at this point in time no one
wants to go to a hospital but it that
doesn't mean our customers should suffer
so we've actually tied up service with
service providers to provide home you
know care for you for our customers for
kovat or non-coated
cases both so these are you know very
very you know first to the market kind
of initiatives that we've already
launched and we believe the long term
that we have you have to come look at
their complete health care service for a
customer rather than just IPD which as
of now mostly of most of the market just
focuses on sandy you want to add
anything i think pretty much well
covered and all the key things that we
wasn't seeing the customers on the
retail side in particular community part
have started looking at having a health
policy both for my investment standpoint
rather than an expense mentality so one
of the few things which is changing and
has seen us on gonotes over to drive on
then a different benefit I think as
Bhargav also mentioned will build up as
in men disbursements coming to benefit
traditionally of Anna separation this
cover which will happen
as you see our banking partners and our
MPs use progressively start deliver
single each one of them is I think till
at least last one getting their credit
strategy in place and you would probably
see a little better quarter to then
what's happening for the one on that if
professor and just a point on the large
stretches of health so compared to cube
for we saw it sector deteriorating so
like seventy to seventy-five percent so
already it Baxter Cooper you want to
explain that so a jokes what happens in
setting loss ratio is purely a function
of what mix of business that you write
and ask you a kind of explained in terms
of corporate generally tends to have
relatively higher lost issues as
compared to let's say the extent of lost
issues that you will get to see on the
retail indemnity portion so that's one
the second element is with respect to
when you look at health else also
includes the retail benefit component
and in this quarter as you would have
seen the extent of loss ratios that you
would have extra the benefit portfolio
contribution is relatively fast over and
generally benefit is a profitable book
on the aggregate when you look at the
overall loss ratios for health water for
was update over eighty four point eight
I mean quarter one of this here is at
eighty five point seven so in that sense
it's not a material movement in terms of
the overall numbers it's really a
function of what mix of business that
you write water one generally tends to
be far more heavy in terms of corporate
because bulk of the corporate strain to
renew their policies and q4 generally
tends to be more relatively skewed in
terms of retail where the gender loss
experience of the retail indemnity book
is lower which prettier forms to the mix
opposes it and just to add one more
point while you shouldn't look at just
the loss ratio because the expenses are
different across these two that do two
categories the b2b the corporate
business pure corporate business
employer for you know where we cover
implies the distribution cost is
relatively less pure retail the
distribution cost is higher so when we
look at the business we look at
in aggregate the combined Asian God sir
surrender this new products like
artisans in the end all this covert
liquid products so what is your sense
like going forward okay little bit co-ed
but this argue essentially do you think
like that portion will grow
substantially and they think that that
makes more money for you or your
pure-play products are making more money
structurally speaking rolling over what
we've done is we've kind of segmented
the market we believe that there is a
segment of market which today was not
buying the traditional covers or typical
mediclaim policies you know that we sell
through our you know retail agency force
because of expense maybe it was expenses
maybe you know each one of us have our
own terms and conditions of maybe it was
getting too complex for the retail
customer so this is the whole thought
process behind this from the regulator
was to have a very standardized product
so there is no dissonance or gradually
at least the the hope is that there
won't be any dissonance in terms of
understanding of what you bought so if
what you if you what a standard are us
engineering product from insurer a
versus insurer be there is no difference
so it will and I strongly support this
thought process because we believe that
in the long term in a very underrated
market like India it is important to
build credibility on the product and in
a product like insurance if you have too
much radiation while it is fine for
maybe slightly more sophisticated
customers for you know new to the
category customers it's good to have a
basic product that they understand
easily so it will we believe open up a
market for that segment of customers
also geographically and you know in
terms of income profile there could be a
because these are slightly restricted
covers it's not as full-blown as some of
the other covers that we have so it's
slightly cheaper so we expect a certain
segment of customers you know wanting to
buy this now profitability will depend
on whether we have done the segmentation
right and whether we are actually
bringing new customers to the book
than cannibalizing our existing
customers that's something that we have
to watch very very closely but we
believe in the long term this is a very
positive development it will depend on
the execution in terms of whether we
actually get to get the benefit thank
you
before we take the next question we'd
like to inform participants that in
order that the management is able to
address questions from all participles
in the conference please limit your
questions to two per participant should
you have a follow-up question we request
you to rejoin the queue you take the
next question
from the line of unshod irony from
Edelweiss please go ahead
I'm sure their knee from Edelweiss you
may go ahead with the question
there seems to be
spawns from the line of Angelini people
to the next question the next question
is from the line on my third letter from
HDFC securities please go ahead
hi everyone or thanks to the immigration
or so can you give us some color on how
renewals in our water had behaved during
the lockdown a leasing signal levels in
PP + mo d were separately and other
things it all lapses happened some some
talk process from Colorado will be
helpful yeah I think we talked about the
fact that in April the renewals will
slightly down you know given the leeway
that was given to you know by the
regulator to renew if customers wanted
with a lag that was not surprising and
also given what was happening on the
ground what we had anticipated was that
people will come back and renew a bit
later so the renewal rates for T plus 1
as in you know what you know in Venice
Italy you've got people who renew within
the same month versus people who renew
the next month or renew in the next
month after that those percentages have
gone up so in a sense we've kind of been
recovering the reduction in renewal
rates that we saw in the April and this
is increasing every month
Sanji if you want to give any more color
to that no absolutely I'd show the
service what happened a prince again
they were that the gap for Delta was
almost more than 12 to 15 percent if you
talk about gunas it it's pretty much
close to what we had free code level it
comes of everyone still marginally less
but nothing much to worry about and did
you believe that we will have a decent
in us because a lot more mobility has
also started across the country and
consequent to that people who actually
defaulted in the month of April and
should come back and seek renewal so we
are pretty much sorted on that and there
was a disposition from the regulator
till of May 15th and thereabouts and
after that these customers are denying
it so we don't see for any challenge
here on private car and TP any betrayed
for the new stock that was sold last
year
has a long-term duration so anyway the
customer has been having a long-term
policy in them
that could something for all the best
thanks but thank you
the next question is from the lineup
Latif ODOT from the porn India mutual
fund please go ahead
yes sir you had written up crop is here
I mean it's very small I understand 1%
but maybe there's the thought process
are you seeing then the markets that the
rates have I mean hardened then that is
why you know it's just an old policy
because the data comes in with a lag
from the government at time it's the old
policy we've not written a ting you okay
answer the second on health insurance
you talked about you know that core it
could be an inflection point for a
selling of health products but if I look
at the mix the mix system it's skewed
towards b2b rather than we will be
slightly to be to see so maybe some Cod
person as to why is that so that in
photo one because I would have a zoom
for the ones up here would have DD is
and hence the pull de montreuil VD is
but a bit surprised when I saw that the
individual numbers of that and a yoy
basis and it comes to them sergey volkov
i'll say that so with respect to quarter
one big is I think sequentially the
demand is picking up when the logged on
children's it was at a very sharp level
at that point of time I think even the
consumers the kind of you know
discovering themselves so from that
perspective now the demand is picking up
even if you look at it internationally
China has the most of the growth in
indemnity help this product happen post
occur with the crisis getting over so we
do believe that euros having a similar
pattern when it comes to demand for this
product up in fact if I just to add
towards and he was saying if you were
slow because as he explained everyone
was probably thinking or other issues
June retail health numbers have been
very very robust for us and we believe
for the industrial so the exit would
have been higher than what you could be
for the quarter average right is that
okay understandings of yes absolutely
and indeed just to give a small
indication even the water for which
typically
has the highest level of agency partners
being active we have seen what's
happened a month of June in particular
we have seen numbers higher than in
March month or you know gentlemen's
agency activation numbers also missing a
very very robust growth and mystery of
New Jersey a lot explained in terms of
what we have done has also helped in
market for me a night session
about products just to add on to that
project I think if you look at the June
exit while you would have seen the
quarter one new in the military growth
rate at 26% if you look at the exit for
the month of June the new indemnity
growth has actually been about 77% Wow
well okay answer lastly just within this
employer employee is it I mean because
there was one regulation in between
there and you know every company had to
take the scoville policy or had to cover
its employees work or the covert related
disease so is it because of that you are
seeing the spike and within this what's
the mix between large corporate made and
small is made or XM is that you can get
back that could be radiating back so
that was MHA but that has not been the
sound getting followed through so you
don't think that it may have had some
initial spike but now that's not the
factor into the mix gopal you want to
answer so I think largely I think I
think what we have always said is we
have tried to keep the grant portfolio
as granular as what we can
our approach pretty much remains is same
on the b2b part of the business we have
so in that sense in terms of the overall
mix the portfolio of large corporates
will tend to be much lower than the SME
portfolio that we have that we write so
for example if you have seen the SME
segment continues to kind of grow robust
on an aggregate basis not specific to
health it should have looked at that is
grown at about 30% but the portfolio mix
is more skewed towards relatively small
and mid corporate accounts as compared
to large corporate accounts secular
Britain great thank you so much and all
the days
thanks for thick thank you the next
question is from the line of son Cade
coda
from spark capital please go ahead yeah
to the opportunity so this is a again
hopping on in the health point so
if I look at absolutely most retail
indemnities are or individual item is
nothing classified in your presentation
that has seen a decline but but we say
that the unity has grown back of the
sick person
so this want you to understand how do I
add up the numbers because the group
others they I believe ppb to see fit
that composition has also come up so so
really Title IV numbers why the recent
health a number those New England it has
grown up but that they absolutely click
will be joining the products so that
it's such question and second question
is is largely with respect to the
motility location which is achieved at
around 70 percentage right now and do
you think it loss ratio E is sustainable
because the committee needs to be too
good and and decide the quite hour to to
low contribution coming off it victory
in the first quarter compared to what it
was for the period of last year and the
mascot of the same here so so even if
the mix is moving in favor also other
products of a reality or intensity are
are higher the most important if you
have improved so this we wanted to over
on the same backbone so I'll ask
Gopal to answer the secretary first
question on the health on the on the
motor TP side you know as we've
discussed many times what we should look
at is the number for the whole year
rather than just a quarter number we may
have had some benefits in terms of for a
quarter you know the some releases there
here or the fact that frequency was
lower in this quarter so you should
watch the number for the whole year
having said that overall the trend in
BTP side is pretty positive we are
seeing frequency drops sustaining into
the mix that you said if the mix is not
deteriorated similar we in fact our CV
Booker's makes us comfortable 14 15
percent two wheeler is about 27% still
in actually private car has increased in
the mix but we do as we said since last
quarter we are actually gradually
increasing our cv exposure a bit again
cautiously because we are seeing some
opportunity
is given underlying changes in behaviors
so on PPV are we are feeling reasonably
comfortable there may be some volatility
in lost issues in a particular quarter
with another quarter but on balance I
think we are reasonably happy with the
TP book that we write the industry
situation because we can't commit on the
health gopal you want to explain the now
in numbers is the issue is the same that
I said you know right you know B to B to
C which is through the bank assurances
come down which has not been we have not
been able to compensate that with the
retail indemnity growth that we sell
through agents in spite of the numbers
that Gopal talked about what Gopal you
want to be more color to a short work
shirt so some kids if you look at the
total retail in the book in terms of
health quarter one last year that number
was roughly about 3.4 billion this
includes both benefit as well as
indemnity put together this quarter that
number is down to about 2.2 billion now
obviously a large part of this decline
it is contributed by the numbers that
were the spoke about in terms of the
benefit portfolio not clearly having a
significant decline on so far as the in
debility segment is concerned with in
written that number is actually
increased from 1.5 billion one point
four seven billion to one point eight
two billion so that's actually an
increase of 23% this is the aggregate
retail health indemnity within that is
what we mentioned about the new retail
ingenuity growth was 25 percent for
quarter one and for the exit month of
June new retail health indemnity or
seventy seven percent okay so what this
is it to satisfy when I do the numbers
then you have given in the presentation
19.5% adjusting gable and complete point
one as in the current year the number
comes to the individual built after one
point seven and one point six four last
year and the currently respectively so I
see a decline around of nine percentage
so screen still ie I'm not able to
figure it out that 1.5 billion and 1.8
billion what you are trying to say stuff
doesn't get thrown a little chain in
there are numbers which you have
disclosed in the presentation
so when you look at the presentation
circuit what happens is obviously there
is some element of eternity that goes
and sits as a part of detail which is
the number that you look at options and
equally there is some element of in
Dometic business that will sit as a part
of group others so when you look at on
switches where I kind of gave the break
up for you in terms of aggregate in the
military book that number has increased
from as I said 1.5 billion to about 1.8
to billion thank you before we take the
next question a reminder to participants
to please limit your questions to 2 per
participant the next question is from
the line of finish on Chandra from
shimmy-shake please go ahead thanks for
taking my question does this also one is
with respect to the claims see
especially on motor what a theme are the
release policy from prior period
especially on people
between March 31 and chambers it has
there been a revision in terms of
assessment for actually in these that we
have there the second one is on the
share value account P R if I remember
correctly for the quarter ending March I
think they've taken some sort of an
inside with respect to exit a book what
is window start givin recovery in
MOSFETs in quarantine soon as the news
reversed or because I couldn't see this
clearly from the financials I can see a
change in revenue save on your home but
I couldn't see whether it was done ku or
the vocal of in silence all the filters
to change
so this reversal of impairment no we've
not done any yes we have done an
impairment because of the sharp
correction in the month of March things
have recovered but we've not done a
reversal of same time and we normally
don't do that I mean we believe that
slightly aggressive in approach so we
don't do that if whenever we sell the
particular stock you will while we could
I mean theoretically VES we could but we
generally don't do that number one and
in the in terms of the provisioning
sorry the reserving policy there's no
change in the policy area nation it's
the same thing which basically every
quarter
you know I've been you know sharing
every month
they are actually underwriting finance
sales all of us sit together and look at
the book you know which are the books
which we believe make sense to focus on
etcetera but on the reserving side they
actually looks at numbers on a quarterly
basis and basis his assessment if he
believes that there is some somewhere we
need to send them something somewhere
the data is compelling that we have to
release we do the release so it could be
there in a certain quarter it's not as
if everything happens at the end of the
year it could be that in certainty of a
certain line and good data because it so
because if there has been a release in
motor TT given that it is of quarterly
number that we are seeing now find it
equal potential grade over two videos
the 70% is not clearly a extendable
thing so the steady state is somewhere
far higher of 70 but there are seen a
release which is pulling that down to
70% is how I interpreted so they
explained earlier because the diseases
you don't need not be spread over the
whole year equally in terms of the
frequency drops that we've seen we've
also not been over aggressive and
booking all of those for the reason that
I articulate because you want to watch
the claims pattern over the year and
then take a fall for the year and I'm
just looking at the presentation it's
priority 5 a period because FY 2013
which in bhopal is diverted into the
response
mission can you just repeat that again
no so if I look at the capo are the
angles in the appendix of the
presentation my understanding is that
the releases all pertain to FY 1984 and
not for FY greenery so this is one
understand of my understanding is
correct so what happens the shunt
insofar as lost experiences are
concerned I think it's purely a function
of the large development that we get to
see across portfolios as we have
explained earlier in respect of short
tail lines their releases tends to be
much faster and in respect of some of
the long tail lines obviously we wait
for certain periods of development
before which we can take a call on the
deserving numbers
so what you get to see is purely a
function of most of the short-tailed
lines that we would have written and
then of course if basis development even
the long tail lines if we get to see a
need for reserving to be relatively
lower then to that extent one would
calibrate the results accordingly when a
frequent is to layer for that to happen
thank you the next question is from
rescission Jun voila from Akai FL please
go ahead
okay the opportunity says it's the
following up on the previous question
and maybe but quickly on motor OBE right
little because of the contributing
lockdown for almost you know two months
and partial of them further assess the
gene as well you wanted to understand I
mean clearly the number of killings that
could have come down later will be
substantially low but what we see in
terms of clean ratios the employment is
not that stark so are we like a
provisioning for claims not reported or
any of that swap in terms of using of
how the individual scales for the rest
of the work because I'm assuming it's a
you know unlike BP it's a 12-month in
and if clean haven't come in three
months then at least four back quarter
the number should have be much better
receive is the same philosophy as I said
in one of the you know questions one
could take the full benefit in a quarter
but we don't believe that's prudent
because we also talk to water in May in
May and just repeat the point that we
believe that people will use vehicles a
bit more when they have to you know
rather than using public transport so
you don't want to have a situation where
you take the full benefit in the quarter
and then to the latter half of the year
your frequency goes up sharply and your
UCAV huge swing so we would I think it's
appropriate to watch the number for the
year rather than take full benefit in
the water so you provided for more in
the so we preach we do a actual estimate
and you know which is a ul our estimate
and that ul our estimate is using data
over a long period of time you know one
blip may not immediately impact the
Euler numbers of course the fact that
frequency is come down in the near term
will have some impact but we would want
to watch the data over a period and as I
said you know for ShoreTel business
let's say like Odie's we will want to
do it in a year for longtail it will be
even longer enough and second one on
hell can you just you know get four
numbers of it opposing thumbs workshop
where we are or on on Kovac related
claim versus raving in the series if it
what you have those numbers and and how
do you expect it to site and very
potentially be as a proportion of your
normal claims that you typically have
just trying to understand basically you
know incrementally how much of you know
the health claims could be coming from
the Cobra's egg hopefully the other
numbers of the covalent I can talk about
be expectation for the future after that
so if you look at Rishi I think the
number of covet claims largely I think
as what we explained with respect to
this particular quarter I think we have
seen more of more of claims coming in in
respect of co-ed treatment for the
quarter obviously that number is roughly
in excess of a thousand claims so as we
speak is closer to maybe about thousand
two hundred thousand three hundred
claims is what we would have seen on the
overall care kovat policy and the amount
involved is roughly about 20 crores or
so so that's the impact for us is with
respect to go with the cases yeah and
for the future Rishi is you know we are
staying cautious we are I you know I
don't think anyone would have predicted
a 1 million number by this time while
you right from beginning we have been
saying if you remember that you know the
the risk is high in this if things on
the kind of taper out sooner so even in
the in the make all we talked about the
fact that the frequency for non covert
claims have come down but we would have
to watch the covert claim so you know
again it's very difficult to predict
this and say that this will go up to a
certain level the numbers are increasing
it's not something that is causing any
your very large concern at this
or panic at this quantitative is but
it's something that we are watching with
with a lot of caution but on balance
given the benefits on the other side the
non covet claims have come we are
hopeful that aggregate for the year
would not be out of line in terms of the
loss ratio but it we could be wrong and
Kovac could go out of control that's the
that's a caveat that I will give in
terms of predicting anything on the last
issue under the headset thank you the
next question is from the line on the
daisy chain from investing asset
management please go ahead
thanks for the opportunity for as I can
you comment on the frequency in the
motor ot and motor TP in the month of
June and how this compared from P Kovac
levels and as we've seen frequency the
external frequency similar to those of
lower than - important that yes so April
the frequency was very very low for
obvious reasons and every month we've
seen significant increase in the
frequencies you month you know at this
point in time would still be maybe 15-20
percent frequency lower than pre Cove it
on the motor road aside but you know
it's a very rapid increase from what we
saw in in April which is also kind of in
line with expectation because for the
reasons that I talked about in earlier
and even now I think some of the bigger
cities the vehicle usage is still muted
so we are you know kind of in line with
our anticipation and expectation we
believe the frequency will go back to
normal you know in due course which is a
reason why we are saying this should be
looked at with the annual length rather
than a 14 which effectively what is the
reason for business for motion expense
remain effect because I believe this
year to change this quarter the same
from the motor side has been quite muted
in that line so whatever your business
promotion expense being move up on a
bottom part is epic go for your answer
so that's primarily because I think is
purely a function of what kind of
opportunities do we see in terms of
growth and as we are kind of explained I
think in disco
relatively the kind of volumes of
opportunities that one would have seen
has been far lower than what we have
seen in the past and as you look forward
and obviously the growth momentum looks
positive and to that extent one would
calibrate the extent of sales promotion
expenses that one would incur in the
current quarter purely driven by the
extent of opportunities that we see on
the revenues and to that extent is very
why you get to see the sales and
promotion expenses pretty much remaining
constant is it a variable line item over
to fix liners and so going probably or
whatever important that it and the
client work power so as I said I think
it will be purely a function of the
opportunity that one one sees in case if
you believe that there are opportunities
to kind of write incremental growth then
obviously we will calibrate and see what
is the extent of sales and promotion
expenses that one will have to income so
it will not necessarily be a cost of a
fixed structure unlike what you see in
terms of employee cost or let's say
infrastructure expenses those are all
our expenses which will be in that sense
completely fixed but so far as
advertisement sales promotion marketing
those are expenses that we calibrate
this is the opportunity that one sees so
for example you would have also seen in
the month of July we kind of launched a
campaign in order to kind of restart the
health opportunity that one sees so
those are have been used through which
we look at playing this through and
grants earlier point it will not
necessarily be here for her course which
will give a fixed nature thank you the
next question is from line of audits
Caravela from ambit capital miss Phyllis
hello am i audible sir yeah yeah so also
my question was that in terms of the
Kadri insurance which you explained and
the cap of around 25 crores is that for
catastrophic event or let's take if you
have two events in a year it will be 25
plus 25 so can you give some dents
around that yeah the answer is yes and
you know basically it's a it's a treaty
that you sign in the beginning of year
which
says and there is a certain clause which
basically says that loss within the
seven days is what is covered as one cat
event but let's say three months but as
Gopal explained we pre agree cost to
reinstate the cover and their finite
number of reading statements that are
also agreed so you reinstate the cover
and the reinstatement cost depends on
how big was the claim so if the if the
insurance paid ten crores and when you
took 25 crores reinsurance to ten crores
then the reinstatement cost will be low
but if spirituals had to pay 500 cause
and the reinstatement cost will be high
so once it's reinstated it's again as if
it's a fresh treaty and let's say six
months later there are another cat and
again it crosses 25 close again we will
take a hit of 25 close and again the
reinsurance will pay the balance but so
in case of Kuwait how Cobra is not kal
Kovac you know Cove it is different Cove
it is a pandemic it's a it's a cat event
so so on that is why you said that it
could water control check would not be
yeah Cove it is not covered by you know
pandemic globally are not covered
because it is not coverable by insurance
without support I do you you would have
an unlimited loss kind of a yes if go
with you know really goes out of control
and you know as a country we are not
able to kind of bring it under control
yes that is a risk we are hoping and at
least our models are not showing
something like this at this point in
time which is why we are saying there we
are watching it with caution it is not
something that we are kind of over
worrying it both because they only
non-covered said there are equally some
savings but on balance that's a risk
that we carry at this point
and one last thing which is related is
that you said around 1200 to 1300 change
in first quarter and the payout was
around 20 crores so which roughly means
that the each claim on an average was
upwards of 1.6 next if I go back to the
calculation which was shared earlier
like in 4q was that you know 50 60
thousand kind of is what the management
was estimating given the treatment cost
may not be high which is not standing
okay
you some sense around that yeah you know
if you've seen the press and the the
overall narrative on what is happening
on the cost of covert treatment and the
reaction of even the policymakers on
what's happening it's obvious that the
covert treatment costs have been
surprisingly high compared to what
probably everyone felt is reasonable and
I think this is one issue that is
becoming quite an issue with between the
pair and the provider industry because
you know we are finding some very you
know
kinnison's outlier claims which we
believe is unreasonable and what it does
is you know even if let's say we end up
paying for the customer it really
affects them it's not as if the customer
is not affected we may be paying the
claim but what happens is if you have a
5x I'm insured and that claim that
logically could have cost one lakh and
it becomes a three-lap you have left
with now two less cover for the rest of
the year because you've consumed three
days of yourself insured so this is an
issue that is becoming quite a issue not
only with the policy makers and you seen
you know actions by state Supreme Court
etcetera but equally between the
insurance industry and the hospital
industry there is a lot of negotiation
and debate going on on what is
reasonable and fair you as we see
there's been a lot of debate and
negotiation and argument that are going
on right now
I think the Koster of completely out of
control in certain places and there
needs to be some reasonableness to the
cost thank you we'll be able to take one
last question we take the last question
from the line of nation schwate from
Kotick please go ahead
yeah hi inaudible now yes here they
should nice ok this stuff one or two
things so what really happened on the
solvency that item a thousand Syrian
supporter go buddy
so nations I think what we kind of also
explained the last quarter is I think
when you look at the solvency in so far
as to three aspects one is with respect
to the fair value change account
movement that you had seen insofar as
solvency regulations are concerned on
the equity side the regulation
disregards any gains if at all is there
on the mark to market position on the
reporting date however if there is a
loss that has to be considered for the
purposes of solvency and if you would
have seen on 31st of March we had a
master market loss of roughly about four
hundred thirty course that was
considered as a part of the solvency
computation on 31st March as a 30th June
if you would have seen our mock to
market on the equity portfolio as as
compared to four hundred thirty crores
of loss is has ended the portfolio with
a 38 crores of loss so that clearly is a
function of the movement that one sees
in so far as improvement in solvency is
concerned the second is also purely a
function of what you get to see in terms
of incremental revenue growth in this
quarter at the pretty much similar to
what the industry is experiencing one
has seen a relatively lower top-line
growth or a t growth to the extent of
litter four five percent or so and that
by itself also kind of contributes to
the improvement in solvency and the
third factor is let's say the
performance in terms of our operating
outcomes on the profits that we make is
also a contributor to the overall
solvency numbers so a factor of all the
three is what has led to the increase in
solvency moving up from two point one
seven to two point five so and you can
share the number for advanced lithium
for the bottom I think that's whatever
forget last year was at a point two five
at 31st March that number 838 June is
thirty point three one it's almost kind
of that is and just one last question
holds on the outlook for the you know
fourth of competition in motor holding
segment I think they are you know this
time around we are seen
some improvement in the lost fish was
out there so should we say that the
worst of the competitive phase on the
Moto G side is behind us difficult to
say yes in a Devon saying maybe for the
last two calls team lasts maybe about
eighteen months to 24 months industrials
been hurt a lot with on the OD side
because of aggressive competition and
our take was that whether people can
sustain that but you know right now
because of everything that we are saying
the frequency is dropped so one can't
rule out continued aggression on OD side
having said that as I said you as
premiums frequencies come back the short
benefit of maybe one or two months may
not sustain in which case it will be
very difficult for people to be further
aggressive on the OD say o DS office
issues are probably unsustainable for
most companies at this point just one
last one you know on the college side I
think what you put you highlighted was
at MIT that you have four policy claims
around two lakh rupees so I think we are
you pointed to a number let's go to that
so I was wondering stalled over a number
which is a lower number than that but
anyway tell me so what do you really do
you think of somebody only Titletown I
guess with the negotiations etcetera
that happens without stress
look you know again as we speak there is
a lot of you know discussion and
negotiation going on I won't want to
hazard a guess on this call and give you
a guidance that I could be wrong with or
weekly we are trying to attempt to bring
it under control our sense is that it's
at this point in there is not reasonable
cost with all but it depends on many
factors right location the severity the
comorbidity which which links it to the
length of stay for the patient whether
the case is mild severe critical so
there are many factors and the mix is
what determines finally the cost because
you know hospitals also have to get a
fair cost if it's a critical case in ICU
ventilator etc versus someone the mild
just being a kind of under observation
so it depends on all of the mix but we
will have a C important 15 I know you
know I really can't give you any comfort
on very productive okay thank you very
much all the best transition thank you
very much we will take that as the last
question I would like to hand the
conference back to mr. Bhargav
descriptor for closing comments so thank
you everyone thanks for joining us at
this time and you know and again wish
all of you good health and take care of
yourself thank you